{
    "id": "f1bf113a1f8e44269735b36ac198160c",
    "title": "Tenses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I will phone you when I ……………………",
            "description": "When both clauses refer to the future, we use the simple present in the subordinate clause.",
            "answers": [
                "arrive",
                "will arrive",
                "would arrive"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "1af1bff9ed5743fdbfbc338f25df686d"
        },
        {
            "question": "He told me that he ……………………….. me.",
            "description": "When the verb in the main clause is in the past tense, we use a past tense in the subordinate clause as well.",
            "answers": [
                "will help",
                "would help",
                "helps"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "03821625c9ab41348c8711907ff379ab"
        },
        {
            "question": "People disliked her because she ………………………. arrogant.",
            "description": "When the verb in the main clause is in the past tense, we use a past tense in the subordinate clause as well.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "was",
                "has been"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "88f29dc886d6430b94aff8c5ab0a895b"
        },
        {
            "question": "We brought the food and they …………………………. the tickets.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "were buying",
                "had bought",
                "bought"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "79621922fe69440e9b2d96aa0fd2d832"
        },
        {
            "question": "She was rich and famous but few people ………………………… her.",
            "description": "Like is not normally used in the continuous form. ",
            "answers": [
                "liked",
                "were liking",
                "are liking"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "248fed5369d54517ae67bca0819d8c0c"
        },
        {
            "question": "I waited for hours so that I ……………………………… her.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "can",
                "could",
                "would"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "0c45cfa2505f4fd2a49fd84b48538549"
        },
        {
            "question": "I went to bed early because I ………………………. not feeling well.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "am",
                "was",
                "had"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "6d59432d7eb24274bd4865832d589ddd"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you need help, just ………………………….. me a call.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "give",
                "gave",
                "giving"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "7e69eb6b382d4550993b01b71d724155"
        },
        {
            "question": "While I ………………………….. a shower, I slipped on the floor.",
            "description": "We use the past continuous for a longer background action that was going on while another action interrupted it.",
            "answers": [
                "had",
                "am having",
                "was having"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "0a7a55cdf4b04811b8af3f4c7a6c4c06"
        },
        {
            "question": "He talks as if he ………………………….. rich but he isn’t.",
            "description": "We use a past tense with a present meaning after as if and as though to show that a comparison is unreal.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "was",
                "had been"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "b77fd731ca7442c2b13ce928ae295964"
        },
        {
            "question": "As well as …………………………. his knee, he broke his arm.",
            "description": "When we put a verb after as well as, we most often use the ing form.",
            "answers": [
                "injuring",
                "injured"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "d303bdd1937d4dbbbda845d74b801f46"
        },
        {
            "question": "While you ……………………………. TV, I was working.",
            "description": "Progressive forms are used in both clauses to talk about two actions that go on at the same time. ",
            "answers": [
                "watched",
                "are watching",
                "were watching"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "a0ceae3c5b77416393ece81f112e18bc"
        }
    ]
}